**CURRICULAM VITAE** 

Mekala Bhavani Prasad

**2**: +91-7981404288

<u> bhanuprasad22061997@gmail.com</u>

**Career Objective:** 

To seek a challenging career in an organization having the environment that encourages continuous learning and provides exposure of new technologies, to achieve professional and personal growth in the field of Information Technology.

**Experience Summary:** 

• Extensive Experience in analysis, designing, developing, support and maintaining N-tier Web Applications using ASP.Net MVC, C#.Net under TFS Environment, Bitbucket Source tree.

• Experience in HTML Designing and Object-Oriented Programming (OOPs).

Experience in Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery.

Good Knowledge in WEB API.

Good Experience in HealthCare domain.

 Good communication skills, Problem solving skills, ability to work under pressure, withstanding long working hours and ready to accept any challenging assignments.

**Experience:** 

• Working as a Software Developer in **Techies infotech Pvt ltd.**, **Bangalore** from June 2022 to May 2023.

• Working as a Software Developer in Techfosys software solutions Pvt Ltd. Chennai from June 2023to November 2023.

**Educational Qualification:** 

 Graduation: Electrical & Electronics Engineering from Mother Teresa institute of Engineering & Technology affiliated to JNTUA Ananthapuram with 72% marks in the year 2019.

**Technical Skills:** 

Operating Systems : Windows Server 2008 R2 / Windows 10.

Development Tools : Dot Net Framework 4.8, LINQ, Visual studio 2019.

Programming Languages : C#. Net 4.7.1, ADO.NET Entity Framework 5.0.

Web Technologies : ASP.NET MVC, HTML, ¡Query, VUE JS, Bootstrap.

Databases : SQL Server 2014.

### Project-1: Med Coding 2.0

**Tools Used**: Visual Studio 2019, .Net Framework 4.8, Azure

**Technologies** : ASP.Net MVC, C#.Net, SQL Server 2014. **Web Technologies** : Boot strap, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery.

Domain : Health Care domain Role : Dot Net Developer.

Team Size : 5

**Duration**: Jun2022 to May 2023.

# **Description:**

The motto of building this application is to accommodate all the existing applications running on different platforms into one application & if any new client is added, it can be accommodated. The main advantage of this application is Customizable Input, Output and Reports. This application is used for medical coding. Cross mapping of ICD-9 with ICD-10 or vice-versa is allowed based on DOS with the implementation of ICD-10 coding in US Health Care industry. Auto-coding process is enabled by capturing all required codes (CPT, PQRS, ICD-9, ICD-10, modifiers etc.) in the medical record with appropriate analysis to improve the quality of codes captured.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Involved in Designing Pages using HTML and Bootstrap, ASP. Net MVC and coding business layer using C#. NET.
- Using Bootstrap, jQuery, JavaScript, and Html for front-end development.
- Designing, Developing, Maintaining, and reviewing Requirement Document.
- Involved in writing Stored Procedures, Joins and functions in SQL Server.
- Using Postman for testing Api calls
- Using Source Tree for code check in.

# **Project-2: City Bank**

**Tools Used**: Visual Studio 2019, Jira, Bitbucket, Visual Code

**Technologies**: ASP. Net MVC, C#.NET, SQL Server

Web Technologies : jQuery, Html, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap

**Domain** : Bank domain

Role : Dot Net Developer

Team Size : 7

**Duration** : June 2023 to November 2023

#### **Description:**

Workflow consists of two modules Business Unit Attestation and Reconciliation. The Business Units that interact with Principal Shareholder should provide attestations of activities and on a quarterly basis to ensure accurate data and effective monitoring practices. To ensure the accuracy of the daily exposer dashboard, a workflow/tracking mechanism should be developed to ensure that all the activities and exposures with the Principal Shareholder are identified and confirmed in the form of reconciliation attestations.

# Responsibilities:

- Involved in Designing Pages using HTML, Bootstrap, java Script, jQuery, Asp.net MVC using C#. NET.
- Designing, Developing, Maintaining, and reviewing Requirement Document.
- Involved in writing Stored Procedures, Joins and functions in SQL Server 2014.
- Using Jira for creating stories, bug.
- Using Bitbucket repository for code clone and check in.
- Using Postman for testing Api calls

Date:

Place: Hyderabad Mekala Bhavani Prasad